--==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩影视 请访问 http://cmct.cc
影片压制: 犇犇    字幕制作: 犇犇
招募Q号: 76846146
演员:阿诺史瓦辛格
片名：魔鬼孩子王
潘妮洛普安蜜勒
Excuse me.
对不起
Shithead.
浑球
You shouldn't be here.
你不该来
I know. Ask for at least $1,000, okay? I'll get as much as I can. You hide.
起码叫价一千元 我尽可能抬价 你躲起来
His wife took his kid and a couple of million... and we won't get a thousand.
他老婆带走儿子和几百万元 应该要一千元
Shut up and stay hidden. I told him I was coming alone.
闭嘴 躲起来 我答应单独来
编剧：墨瑞赛林 赫雪温格 提摩西哈里斯
制片：伊凡瑞特曼 布莱恩格拉赛
Hey, Mr. Crisp. How's it going?
克利先生 你好吗？
导演：伊凡瑞特曼
You said you had information about my family.
你有我妻儿的消息？
Yeah, yeah, I do.
是呀 我有
Well, let's have it.
好 说给我听
Well, it's going to cost you.
你得花钱
Like $1,000?
一千块钱
Okay, that's obviously not my final offer. 750 would be fine.
这显然不是底价 750元也好
I mean, more than fine.
不仅是好
Just tell me what you have, Danny... and I'll take good care of you.
说给我听 我会好好赏你
Okay. That sounds fair.
好 这话很中听
I was doing a delivery for Corky last week out of state... and I ran into your ex.
上周我给高基跑腿 见到你前妻
How'd she look?
她怎么样？
She looked great, Mr. Crisp. Yeah.
很漂亮 克利先生
She changed her hair and stuff... but she looked like a million dollars.
发型改了不过容貌值百万元
In fact, she looked like about $3 million.
其实她卷三百万元逃走
Did she see you?
她看见你没有？
No. I was changing a tire...
没有 我正换轮胎
and suddenly, there she was across the street... taking her kid into this school.
她过马路送她儿子上学
My boy?
我儿子
Looked great. He looked very healthy.
他很好 很健康
It's a real nice, healthy place where they're living.
定居的地方优美宽阔
It snows in winter there.
冬天下雪
Danny...
丹尼
where are they?
他们在那儿？
At the school where I saw them...
在那所学校被我看到
Astoria Elementary School. That's...
爱莎利亚小学
It's in Astoria, Oregon.
奥勒冈州爱沙利亚镇
Oregon.
奥勒冈
All right. Did you tell anyone else this?
有没有告诉别人？
No. No way.
绝对没有
Hey, I'm not stupid, Mr. Crisp.
我不笨 克利先生
You're not?
你不笨？
Danny.
丹尼
Danny! No!
Danny!
丹尼
Danny! Get up!
丹尼 起来
Don't you die on me!
不要丢下我自己死
I didn't kill him. I didn't kill him.
我没杀他
Was it Crisp?
克利杀的？
I don't know. I didn't see anything.
不知道 没看见 我在纸箱里
What are you doing?
你干什么？
Hey, hey, hey!
嗨 嗨 嗨
Stop it! Don't do that!
住手
Don't go anywhere.
不要乱跑
Let me go!
放我走
No! Let me off of him!
让我同他分开
I don't like what you've done. I really don't like it.
你做的发型我不喜欢
It feels terrible, and it looks dreadful.
真难看 令我呕气
I'm trying my best.
我已尽力
Maybe your best isn't good enough.
还是不好
I'm back.
我回来了
Oh, great. Well, that was fast. It was easy.
你办事好快 轻而易举
I have some great, exciting, wonderful news, Mother.
妈 有令人兴奋的消息
Oh, you always exaggerate, Cullen.
孤冷 你老爱夸张
Everything is always great, terrific. So, what's so great?
样样都说得美 什么好消息？
I just found out where they're hiding.
我晓得他们藏身之地
Are you serious? You really know where he is?
当真？你晓得儿子下落？
Manicure, Mr. Crisp?
修指甲？克利先生
Oh, how could I say no to you?
我怎么舍得回绝你？
Tell me. What's happened?
怎么回事？告诉我
Just let me handle this myself, Mother. I know what I'm doing.
妈 这件事让我处理 我自有分寸
Everything is under control.
都在我掌握
It's all right. I'm a police officer.
我是警察
Crisp, you're under arrest.
克利 束手就擒
Put your hands on your head and get up!
双手抱后脑 起立
Kimble, not again!
金霸 别再烦我
Your hands!
双手抱头 手举起了
They're up. When will you leave me alone?
几时你才罢休？
Drop the gun!
把枪丢掉
对 把枪丢掉
Hey, I'm a police officer. This is an arrest.
我是警察 抓人犯
This man's crazy. Look at him.
这个人是疯子
He'll kill me. You're just going to stand there?
他要杀我 制止他
Freeze!
不准动
I'm a cop!
我是警察
I'm Detective John Kimble.
约翰金霸警探 抓人犯
This man is under arrest. I'm checking.
我正在查询
You can't just walk in here and put a gun in my face.
你不能持枪闯进来
I'm trying to get a manicure.
我来此修指甲
I have witnesses.
有人证
I have a witness, too.
我也有人证
It's murder one this time.
这回是一级杀人罪
Now you're mine.
你被我逮到了
The bastard handcuffed me to a dead man!
那浑帐把我同死人铐在一起
A dead man!
死人
Come on. Sit down.
坐下
Now, did Danny ever say
丹尼可曾提到
what Crisp's wife looked like? No.
克利老婆的长相？
Did he ever say what name she was using in Oregon?
可提到她用什么化名？
He didn't say anything. Look, I just want to go home.
他没说 放我出去
After the lineup, I'll drive you home. I'll even buy you dinner.
等指认凶嫌后我送你回家 还请你吃晚饭
I'll even cook you dinner. I'm not doing any lineup...
我下厨做给你吃如何？我不要指认
and there ain't jack shit you can do about it!
你能拿我怎么样？
I've been after Crisp for four years... and she's letting my key witness walk away?
我盯克利有四年了 不能放过
Kimble, sit down!
金霸 坐下
Sit down. - Sit. - Sit.
坐下 坐下
Now listen to me. He killed your boyfriend.
听着 他杀你的男友
All you have to do is point your finger...
只要你指一指
and we can put him away for 30 years.
我们拿他下狱
He wasn't my boyfriend. I hardly knew the guy.
不是我的男友 萍水相逢
I know you're in there.
我知道你在那边
I know what you want, but you ain't getting it.
知道你要什么
No lineup, no testimony.
你休想如意
So shove your handcuffs up your ass!
带着手铐去你的
Now let me out of here!
放我出去
Slow down!
别冲动
Open it and let me out!
开门 让我出去
O'Hara, meet Kimble.
奥哈拉 见过金霸
Kimble's been on this a long time. Hi.
他盯克利很久了
Let me take care of Cindy.
我来对付仙蒂
She'll make Crisp. I guarantee it.
她会指认克利
What are you going to do...
怎么对付？
handcuff her to your car and take her for a ride?
把她铐在保险杠上
I'm not going to offer to cook her dinner.
我不会做晚饭给她吃
Kimble, hold on a second. I...
金霸 等一下
Difficult man. Got to get to know him. Oh, I can't wait.
你得多了解他 迫不及待
Hey, baby.
嘿 宝贝
What you mean, " Hey, baby"?
怎么叫他宝贝？
Shit!
厉害
Oh, excuse me. I forgot to introduce myself.
对不起 我忘了通报姓名
My name is John Kimble...
我叫约翰金霸
and I love my car.
深爱我的车子
I'll keep an eye on it for you.
我帮你看守车子
You got a beautiful ride.
你的车漂亮
Shit. Who does he think he is? He's lucky I didn't kick his ass.
我不出手算他走运
Open up.
开门
You can't come in.
你不能进来
Thank you.
谢谢你
What the fuck?
他妈什么事？
All right...
好了…
party's over. Everyone go home.
席散了 大家回去
Next time, my place.
下回在我家聚会
So who are you, man?
你是谁？
Shit!
要老命
I'm the party-pooper.
我无扫人家的兴
Hi, Cindy.
嘿 仙蒂
Do you mind if I sit down?
我坐下你可在意？
No. Sit down, man.
不敢 老兄 请坐
Oh, it's so nice to see you again.
又见你真好
What are you doing here, you asshole?
你来干什么 浑蛋？
Cindy, I don't like you using foul language...
你骂脏话我不喜欢
not a classy girl like you.
你有气质
Don't you have anything better to do?
你没别的事好干？
You don't understand. I have nothing else to do...
你不明白 我没别的事
and I have nowhere else to go.
而且也没别处可去
Why are you staring at me like that?
干嘛瞪着我？
I like you, Cindy.
仙蒂 我喜欢你
I'm going to be around you a lot...
要常在你左右
days, nights, weekends, holidays.
日日夜夜不分周末假日
No. No, you can't.
你不可以
Yes, I can.
可以
I'm going to hang out with you until the end of time.
我要守着你 天长地久
All right, move it in.
快上去
Let's go.
快
Step onto the numbers.
站在号码上
Face front.
面向前方
Everybody, hands to your side.
两手自然下垂
That's the creep.
就是那个瘪三
Who? Number five.
谁？
That's him.
五号 就是他
Good. Very good.
好 很好
Mr. Crisp, you will be remanded into custody until your trial.
将你收押直到出庭受审
Bailiff, remove the prisoner.
法警 押犯人下去
Shh. Don't say anything. Just take it easy. I'll take care of it. Trust me.
别说话 放轻松 我来处理 放心
You know what to do?
你可有办法？
I'm your mother, aren't I?
我是你娘对不对？
Mind if I talk to my friend a little bit?
我跟我的朋友谈
I'm not talking to anybody without my lawyer.
律师不在我不跟你谈
He's right in here.
律师在里面
You give me the names of your drug suppliers and distributors...
供出毒品来源
and I'll tell the judge what a nice, cooperative killer you are.
我找法官讲情 说你这凶手听话肯合作
You think the jury's going to convict me on the testimony of that junkie?
陪审不会听那吸毒女子的话 判我有罪
You could be right.
你的话也许对
But what about your wife?
可是你老婆呢？
You remember her?
可记得她？
All that hard-earned drug money she stole from you?
卷走你贩毒的昧心钱
How much was it...
盗走多少钱？
$3 million?
三百万元？
I bet she would make a much better witness.
她出庭作证更有效
Kimble, you've wasted years chasing after me... and what has it gotten you, hmm?
金霸 你盯我耗了几年 为了什么？
Nothing.
什么都没
I'll be out in a week...
不为什么
and you'll still be eating take-out food in that dump you live in.
不久我就自由 你仍旧吃便当
Yeah, I know all about you, Kimble.
金霸 我看透你了
Without me, you wouldn't even have a life.
少了我你顿失生活的目标
My old lady left 'cause of the money.
我老婆为了钱遗弃我
Yours left because she just couldn't stand the sight of you.
你老婆眼里容不下你而离开
I've never seen anyone so little eat so much.
个子小胃口那么大？
Yeah, I know. I'm hypoglycemic. If I don't eat regularly... I get a little nuts.
我患低血糖 若不经常吃会发狂
So... where you from?
你祖籍那里？
Austria.
奥地利
How long you been a cop?
当警察多久了
I been a cop for 12 years.
十二年
My father was a cop... my brother was a cop... my mother was a cop's wife.
父亲和兄长当警察 我妈当警察的老婆
And I have no hobbies.
我没有嗜好 有好消息
You two are booked on the first flight to Portland tomorrow.
明天你二人飞到波特兰
Locate Crisp's wife and offer her immunity
找克利的老婆以豁免权
in exchange for her testimony against him.
交换她出庭作证
No offense to O'Hallahan... but this is my case, and I work alone.
奥哈拉汉 别见怪 这件案子我要独自办
He works alone. Not anymore.
独来独往改观了
She's going in undercover as a substitute kindergarten teacher.
她要扮幼稚园老师代课卧底
Not exactly a job for you.
这差使你不合
I used to be a teacher. We'll be fine.
我干警察之前当过老师
What do I do?
我做什么？
She locates the kid... you find the mother and the cash...
她找小孩 你找母亲和脏款
and Crisp spends his life making license plates.
克利终生坐牢在监狱制牌照
Bon voyage.
一路平安
Oh, and, Kimble, the name's O'Hara.
金霸 我姓奥哈拉
OK. Here's the wife at 17. Real name's Rachel Myatt.
他老婆17岁的照片 本名瑞雪梅雅
She's from Hannibal, Missouri, class of '76.
密苏里人 当过啦啦队长
Cheerleader, first violin in the school orchestra...
高中交响乐团小提琴手
captain of the girls' softball team.
垒球队长
Her ambition was " To travel... experience life...
立志要旅游 体验人生结交朋友
and meet interesting people." Like Crisp.
结交克利之流？
Okay.
好的
Relax. Don't let him get to you.
别激动 不要意气用事
That's her 10 years later.
她高中毕业后十年的照片
It's a great shot of an ear. You get in touch with her parents?
照相技术真高 她的双亲呢
They're both dead.
都死了
The only relative she's got left is the kid.
儿子是她仅有的亲人
Hey.
嗨
Okay. This is the only picture we have of him.
警方仅有他这张照片
Cullen Jr., aged 3 months.
孤冷二世 三个月大
That helps much.
真管用
It's the best I could do.
我只弄到这张照片
Breakfast, sir? Ma'am?
吃早餐？拜托
Please. No. No, no.
不吃
That's a first.
头一回拒吃
Listen, I was just thinking.
我刚想到
Maybe we should take a wild stab at getting to know each other before we
我们应该彼此多了解
have to pretend we're married.
才好冒充夫妻
What do you want to know? How long have we been married?
想了解什么？我们结婚多久了？
A long time. People won't expect us to talk much to each other.
很久了 彼此不理睬很正常
I want to read it, too.
杂志给我 我也要看
Stop it. Please?
住手
Let me take a look.
拜托给我 给我看
Hey, come here.
过来
If you don't stop screwing around back there...
要是你不停止捣蛋
this is what I'll do with you.
要你像这支铅笔
Ohh.
噢
What's the matter? I don't know.
怎么回事？不知道
I just don't feel so good.
怎么了？胃不舒服
You hungry?
饿不饿？
I got to get out of here right now.
马上要上洗手间
Get those tree stumps out of my way before I vomit all over them.
移开你的树干腿 免得我吐在你身上
Is your wife okay, sir?
你太太要不要紧？
Compared to what?
拿什么时候比？
Maybe it was the burrito.
也许玉米饼吃坏肚子
Or it could've been the sausages.
或者是香肠不卫生
I don't think it was the crab salad. It couldn't have been the doughnuts.
蟹肉沙拉和甜甜圈 不会有问题
Excuse me.
对不起
Oh, I hate feeling like this.
闹肠胃真可恶
I hate it, too.
我也憎恶
Uh-oh.
呃
Uh-oh what? Uh-oh...
什么？
pull over.
停车
Now? Yeah. Please hurry.
马上停？是呀 快点
The key! Give me the key!
厕所钥匙
Do you need a hand?
要不要帮忙？
You okay? I'm fine.
你好吗？很好
I'll be fine.
不要紧
Class starts at 9:00 in the morning.
明天九点才上课
I'll be fine.
到时就好了
You look much better already.
你的气色好多了
Oh. Kindergarten, 6-year-olds.
幼稚园 六岁儿童
That's why I quit teaching, you know.
所以我辞掉教职
I got so sick of other people's kids.
别人的小孩烦死我了
I was afraid that I'd never want to have any of my own.
教下去 只有自己都不想生孩子
I have a son.
我有个儿子
He's 13.
十三岁了
I remember when he was 5.
我记得他五岁的样子
He lives with his mother and stepfather. Aah!
他跟着母亲和继父
What's the matter?
怎么回事？
What... is... that?
那是什么东西？
Oh, excuse me. I forgot to tell you.
忘了跟你讲
This is my ferret.
我养的雪貂
He doesn't bite. Don't worry.
不会咬人 放心
Come on. Come on out.
来吧 出来
This is all I need... an obstacle.
弄个累赘 真是愈帮愈忙
A goddamn obstacle. He sends me an obstacle. Here.
弄个累赘给我
Oh, God.
我的天
Don't worry.
放心
I'm going to make it.
我一定能代课
I just need a minute.
只要歇一会儿
I'll be ready in just a minute. I just got...
一分钟可以准备好 只要
Oh, God.
我的天
How do I look?
这样打扮如何？
Take off the gun.
取下手枪
That's a good idea.
好主意
The little bastards are going to eat you alive.
那些小杂种会把你生吞活剥
Get some rest, and don't worry.
你安心养病吧
I've been working undercover for a long time.
卧底密探我干很久了
They're 6-year-olds. How much trouble can they be?
六岁孩童能有多大能耐？
On second thought...
再想想
take the gun.
还是带枪的好
Matthew...
马修
I sent you to the principal's office because you punched Jenny.
你打珍妮所以我要你见校长
I know. She poisoned your hamsters.
我知道 她毒死你的大颠鼠
She told me all about it... and she's very sorry.
她跟我说了 还道歉
And I'm sorry that I didn't believe you.
我不相信你 我道歉
- But you shouldn't punch people. - But she...
但不能打人 可是她
I know!
我知道
Mr. Kimble, Miss Schlowski will see you now.
金宝先生 史校长有请
Let's go back to class.
我们回课堂
Can I help you?
有何指教？
I'm John Kimble, your new kindergarten teacher.
我是约翰金霸 新来的老师
We were expecting a Miss O'Hara.
我们等的是奥哈拉小姐
There's been a change of plan.
安排有所变更
Four weeks into the new semester...
这学期剩四周
my superintendent told me I had to replace Mrs. Hagley...
督学要我更换赫老师
a kindergarten teacher of 25 years' experience...
她有廿五年幼教经验
with an undercover police officer... and he wouldn't even tell me why.
却要由密探顶替也不说原委
I don't suppose you would do me the courtesy of filling me in.
我想你也不愿说内情吧？
I can't do that.
我不能说
Oh. You can't do that.
你不能说
I'm watching you.
我会监视你
All I have to do is tell my parents that you're with the police...
我只消对家长说 你是警方的人
and they'll yank their kids out of this school so fast... we'd have to close.
他们会急忙接孩子走 要学校关门
And don't you think I won't if I feel my children are in any danger.
为了学童的安全 我不惜关门
They're not in danger.
学童没有危险
I assume you have some teaching experience.
我猜想你有教学经验吧？
They wouldn't have sent me otherwise.
没有怎么会派我来？
Just wait here a minute.
在门口等一下
Everybody sit down on the carpet!
大家坐在地毯上
Good morning, everyone. Good morning, Miss Schlowski.
小朋友早安 早安 史校长
Your teacher, Mrs. Hagley had to go on an important trip.
你们的老师赫小姐 有要事出远门
Where'd she go?
上那去？
That doesn't matter.
那不重要
Did she die?
她死了？
No, Lowell. She went to see someone.
没死 罗威 她去看别人
Did they die?
别人死了？
No, Lowell.
没死 罗威
Everyone dies, you know.
人都要死
I know, but not for a long, long time.
我知道 但是要活很久才死
Now, until Mrs. Hagley comes back...
赫老师回来之前
we have someone special to help.
我们特别请了人帮忙代课
This is Mr. Kimble... your new kindergarten teacher.
这位是金霸老师 你们的新老师
Now, let's everybody say,
大家一起说
"Good morning, Mr. Kimble."
金霸老师 早安
Good morning, Mr. Kimble.
早安 金霸老师
Good morning.
早安
They're all yours.
都交给你了
I'll be watching you.
我会监视你
Hi.
嗨
How are you?
大家好
I'm very happy to be here.
来到这里很高兴
First I would like to just get to know you.
首先我要认识大家
Quiet.
肃静
I'm going to ask you a bunch of questions.
我要问你们一些问题
I want to have them answered immediately.
你们要立刻回答
How many of you were born in Astoria?
有多少人在爱沙利亚出生？
Raise your hands. Let's see them.
举手
Okay, hmm.
好吧 嗯
Now, anyone that was not born in Astoria...
谁在爱镇以外出生
somewhere outside like California... raise your hands.
譬如加州 举手
Yes.
是的
I need to go to the bathroom.
我要上洗手间
Okay. You can go.
好 你去
Boys have a penis. Girls have a vagina.
男生有小鸡鸡 女生有小屁屁
Thanks for the tip.
谢谢你的情报
Yes?
是？
I need to go to the bathroom... and I can't get these things off.
我要上厕所解不开吊带扣
I'll get someone to help you. I'll be right back, okay?
我找人帮你解 马上来
You've learned that the " e" is often silent
你们知道"e"字母
when it immediately follows another vowel.
接另一母音则常常不发音
Now write and say these words...
抄这些字然后读
Oh, um...
哦 嗯…
class, uh, Catherine...
下课 嗯 凯瑟琳…
can you take over for me, please?
凯瑟琳 请你代一下
Thank you.
谢谢
"E" is the fifth letter of the alphabet.
"E"是字母表中第五个字母
Yes, can I help you?
有何指教？
I have a problem.
我有点困难
Mr. Kimble... I need to go real bad.
报告老师 我的尿好急
First day? Yes.
第一天？是的
I'll take care of her. Thank you.
我来照应她 谢谢
You know, kindergarten is like the ocean.
幼稚园像海洋变化莫测
Don't turn your back on it.
一转身学童就造反
They're okay. Don't worry.
我的学生还好 别耽心
Everything is under control.
都在我掌握中
No.
不好
Monsters.
小妖怪
What are you doing with this?
你拿这个干什么？
Aren't you going to break it up?
你不出面制止？
No. Two more days of this... and he'll quit.
不要 这样再闹两天包他请辞
Shut up!
闭嘴
Shut up.
Shut up!
闭嘴
No. Don't start this.
不行 不要哭
Oh, no...
糟了
Aah!
啊哈
Attention!
注意
This is your new class mascot.
这是班上新的吉祥兽
What happened to your dog?
你的狗怎么了？
This is not a dog.
不是狗
This is a ferret.
是雪貂
What's a ferret?
雪貂是什么？
That's a ferret. Oh!
这就是雪貂
If he bites you, you get rabies and die.
被它咬伤会得狂犬病死跷跷
No. That's not true. He never bites.
没这回事 它不咬人
Can I pet him?
可以摸它？
Sure, but one at a time, okay?
可以 一个一个来摸
Good. Okay, next one. Come on.
好 下一个 过来
Yes. Good.
很好
Yeah.
Good. Now we're having fun.
很好 我们开心的玩
What's that supposed to mean?
什么意思？
Mrs. Hagley is a lot better than you.
赫老师比你好多了
Is she?
是吗？
Is she really?
真的比我好？
My mom's a teacher in this school...
我妈也在学校教书
and she's a lot better than you, too.
她也比你好多了
Great.
很好
On Monday nights, my mom tutors
星期一晚上我妈当家教
and Mrs. Quinn takes care of me. She's better than you, too.
昆恩太太看顾我也比你强
Great.
很好
And Frankie, my swimming teacher... and Gus, my T-ball coach,
我的游泳老师 棒球教练
are better than you, too.
也都比你强
I really appreciate your honesty.
谢谢你说老实话
You happen to know someone that's not better than me?
可认识不比我强的人？
I don't know that many people.
不认识比你差的人
John?
约翰？
Are you there?
你回来了？
How did it go?
情形如何？
Go away.
走开
It went that well, huh?
上课有这么顺利？
You take over tomorrow.
明天你接手
And blow our cover?
暴露身份？
Can't do it.
我不能接
They're horrible.
他们好可怕
Tell me about it.
那还用说
He's gay.
他患同性恋
What kind of a man teaches kindergarten? He's obviously gay.
正常男人那会教幼稚园？
A male kindergarten teacher isn't what I'm used to.
男老师令我不能适应
Samantha calls him "The giant."
莎曼珊叫他"巨人"
There he is. Where, honey?
他来了 在那儿？
Holy cow, is that your new teacher? Yeah.
天啊 你的新老师？
Oh, my God.
我的天
- What are you doing? - I'm not wearing makeup.
- 你干什么？- 我没有化妆
None of us are.
我们都没化妆
You're married. You're allowed to look like slobs.
你有老公 邋遢没关系
Be good. I'll be back to pick you up.
要听话 我会接你放学
Good morning, Mr. Kimble.
金霸老师 早安
Good morning.
早安
I told you he was big.
我说过他高大
Play with the kids, honey.
去同小朋友玩
Hi. I'm Jillian, Sylvester's mom. Do you have a minute?
我叫姬莲 席维斯的母亲
I'd like to speak with you.
耽误一分钟同你谈谈？
Sure.
好呀
Please. Thank you.
请坐 谢谢
A male kindergarten teacher. That's unusual.
男人教幼稚园 少见
You're not from around here, are you?
你不是本地人
No. I'm not.
不是
Neither am I. Huh.
我也不是
Anyway...
总之
um...
嗯…
I have a small problem.
小有问题
Yes?
是？
You see, Sylvester's father doesn't live with us anymore...
席维斯的父亲不跟我们住
and I've just been worried about Sylvester.
我一直为席维斯耽心
He's been acting a little strange lately...
最近他举止乖张
You know, doing odd things.
行为有异
Like what?
什么异状？
Well, it seems that's he's becoming a little obsessed with playing with dolls.
玩洋娃娃着了迷
You know, it's weird.
行为怪异
I think I can help you with that.
我能帮忙 真的？
Really? He uses the dolls to look up girls' skirts.
他利用玩洋娃娃 窥看女生裙底
I caught him doing it yesterday.
昨天我见他窥看
Oh. Oh, well, that's a relief.
那我就放心了
But I'll keep an eye on him, okay? Thank you.
不过我会留意他 谢谢
Does Sylvester ever see his father?
席维斯有没有见父亲？
No. No, not since he was 2.
没有 打两岁起就没有
His father lives in California.
他父亲住在加州
That is far away. Mm-hmm.
相隔遥远
Well, if you give me his name and number... I could talk to him
把他的姓名电话告诉我
about taking more interest in his son.
我来请他多关注儿子
That's very kind, but I don't think so.
谢谢你的好意但不用了
But it's tough on Sylvester, don't you think?
席维斯是否难适应？
No. No, what's tough on Sylvester
不会
is his father left us for another man.
他父亲另有男人才令他难受
Are you married, Mr. Kimble?
金霸先生 你结婚没有？
No, I'm not.
没有
He's not married, Mom!
妈 他没有结婚
Welcome to Astoria... the single-parent capital of America.
欢迎 爱镇是单亲家庭之都
Thank you for your time.
谢谢你抽空
I pledge allegiance
本人谨宣誓
to the flag
忠于
of the United States of America...
美利坚合众团国旗
and to the republic for which it stands...
暨国旗代表之共合
one nation, under God...
一统之国家得天庇佑
indivisible...
不可分裂
with liberty and justice for all.
人人自由平等
Are these all your lunches?
餐盒都是你的？
You mean you eat other people's lunches?
你偷吃别人的午餐？
Stop it!
嘴巴停
Now we're going to do something extremely fun.
现在要做有趣的事
We're going to play a game called... "Who is my daddy and what does he do?"
来玩游戏 名称是"我爸爸是谁？做什么事"
Yes?
是？
Is your daddy a fireman?
你爸爸是消防员？
He's probably big. Is he a wrestler?
可能好壮 是不是摔角手？
A basketball coach? No, no.
是不是棒球教练？
What's the matter?
怎么回事？
I have a headache.
头疼
It might be a tumor.
可能是长脑瘤
It's not a tumor!
不是长脑瘤
It's not a tumor at all.
根本不是长瘤
What I meant was...
我是要你们告诉我
you tell me who is your daddy and what does he do?
你们的爸爸是谁？做什么事？
Oh.
哦
Get it? We start right here. You.
懂不懂？从你开始
My dad repairs cars driven by women who are pinheads.
我爸爸修理汽车 笨女人撞坏的车
My dad doesn't do anything since the crash.
车祸以后我爸爸什么都不做
My dad gives money to people that doesn't have money...
我爸爸拿钱给没有钱的人
then people use that money...
那些人拿钱去用
then they give other money back
把多余的钱还回来
and they give the same amount of money back to my dad.
然后把同样多的钱 还给我爸爸
My dad doesn't live with us anymore. He lives in New York and drives a taxi.
我爸不同我们住 他住在纽约开计程车
My mom hopes he's going to die real soon.
我妈希望他快点死
My dad watches TV all day long.
我爸成天看电视
My dad works on computers...
我爸用电脑办公
and he's, um, the boss of his company...
他是公司的老板
and, um, he has a mustache and a beard.
满嘴满脸长胡子
Mm-hmm.
嗯 嗯
Yeah.
呀
He doesn't have that much hair because...
头发却没那么多
and he... his head is so big that he can't wear any hats.
他的脑袋瓜好大 戴不下帽子
My dad's divorced. My mom's divorced.
我爸离婚了 我妈离婚了
My dad, um, is a psychologist...
我爸是精神医师
and he helps people that are hurt or lost their feelings... and, um, that's it.
治疗感情受创伤 或是丧失感情的人 完毕
Our mom says that our dad is a real sex machine.
我们的妈说爸爸是性爱机器
Good.
很好
I don't know what my dad does.
我不知爸做什么事
I haven't seen him in a long time.
好久没见到他了
He lives in France.
他住在法国
My dad is a gynecologist...
我爸是妇科医师
and he looks at vaginae all day long.
成天看屁屁
Thank you. Very good.
谢谢 很好
Okay. Next, uh... What's his name with his back to me?
下一位 背朝我的是谁？
His name's Zach Sullivan. He doesn't like anyone to talk to him.
他叫柴克苏利文 不跟人讲话
He's a poo-poo head.
他脑筋"秀斗"
He's a poo-poo face.
他的脸丑陋
He's a ca-ca poo-poo.
他是狗屎牛粪
He's a poo-poo ca-ca.
他是便便 便便
- Poo-poo ca-ca! - Poo-poo ca-ca!
- 便便 便便 - 便便 便便
Quiet. That's enough.
安静 不要说了
Hey, Zach.
柴克
Did your daddy teach you this game?
爸爸教你玩这种游戏
Come on, Zach. Let's all play together. It's so much more fun.
柴克 跟大家一起玩 更有趣味
Leave me alone!
不要烦我
What's that?
什么声音？
It's a fire alarm!
火警
Come on, come on. Everyone together! Come on.
快点 大家一起 快点
I'm on fire!
我身上着火了
Come on. All together! I'm on fire!
大家在一起 我身上着火了
Very straight. Very straight.
成一路排整齐
Come on, come on. Get all together. Everything together. Come on.
大家在一起 听话 大家在一起
Come on. Quiet. Quiet! Come on.
快走 安静 安静
Shh! Quiet. Well, we're all glad the kindergarten class could join us.
幼稚园同学加入我们真高兴
That's four minutes. You should be ashamed of yourselves.
四分钟 你们应该惭愧
All the other grades... your times were an improvement...
其他各班级使用的时间 有进步
but they're still not good enough.
不过还不够迅速
I'm very disappointed.
我非常失望
All right, let's get back into school.
好 回学校去
Mrs. Sullivan!
苏太太
So the doctor says it's a stomach flu.
医生诊断为感冒
I'm fine. I can eat anything I want.
我很好 不用忌嘴
Let's find a restaurant.
我们找餐厅
Can we talk business?
能不能谈公事？当然
There are 14 boys in the classroom.
我那班有14个男童
So far I have three possible suspects, one likely. Here's a picture. You listening?
有三个可疑 排除了一个 这是他照片 听进去没有？
I'm listening.
我听到了
His name's Zach Sullivan. What do you think?
他叫柴克苏利文
He's cute.
长得可爱
Doesn't anybody eat around here?
怎么没有餐厅？
Listen, he's a dead ringer for Crisp. Look.
长得酷似克利 你看
Maybe. Come on, John. I'm hungry.
也许是 约翰 我饿了
A table for two. Thank you very much.
是 订二人桌 谢谢
Two hot dogs. Two hot dogs?
我要两分热狗 两客？
Mr. Kimble! Mr. Kimble!
金宝先生 金宝先生 多明尼
Dominic. It's him, Mom.
妈 他来了 多明尼
Joyce.
我叫乔伊丝
Hello, Joyce. Dominic has been a great help.
你好 乔伊丝 多明尼是个好帮手
He's a good kid.
他是个好孩子
Who's that?
那个是谁？
Who?
谁
Her.
她是谁？
Oh, that? Uh, that is, uh...
那个 那是
I am his sister.
是他妹子
Oh, really? I wouldn't have guessed.
真的？教人猜不到
You have to excuse my brother. He has no manners.
请原谅家兄 他没礼貌
My name is Ursula. Wonderful to meet you. I'm visiting here from Austria.
我叫乌苏拉 从奥地利来 很高兴见到你们
I'm Joyce Paulmarie. I work at John's school.
乔伊丝波尔马利 跟约翰同事
Ah. And this is Dominic.
这是多明尼 嗨 多明尼
Nice to meet you.
幸会
彼此
Would you like to join us for dinner?
坐一桌好不好？
- No. - Ja.
- 好啊 - 不用
Ja.
好呀
Yes, of course. That would be great.
好 好极了
Hi. There will be four of us.
四人桌
Table 27.
27号桌
Why did you tell her you were my sister?
为什么冒充我妹子？
Relax, butch. The love doctor is here.
别紧张 屠夫 我是爱情神医
Come to me. I want to start.
到我这儿 我先点菜
Okay. I want a rib eye steak with mashed potatoes and a large green salad.
我要牛小排加洋芋泥 大盘青菜沙拉
Oh, no. Wait a minute. I want to start with the spicy chicken wings.
等一下 我先点酱淋鸡翅
Are they the tiny ones without meat?
不是小鸡翅吧？
Actually, it's quite a large serving.
不是 是大鸡翅
Ah, good. Ooh, good arms.
手臂结实
And a large bowl of the clam chowder.
还要大碗杂烩
Uh, and the blueberry pie with ice cream for dessert.
蓝梅派冰淇淋甜点
I like how they talk.
我喜欢他们的腔调
I've been trying to get to know the parents... but some of them are avoiding me.
我想认识家长有些却回避我
Some of them are like that. It's a strange town that way...
有些家长是这样
especially with new arrivals.
新定居的尤其怪异
What do you mean?
什么意思？
I think a lot of people that come to small towns
我认为迁居小镇的人
are trying to get away from something
都是逃亡
or they're hiding something.
或是避祸
Like what?
比方什么？
Well, for example, what brought you here?
比方说 你为何来此？
Me? Well, there was an opening for a kindergarten teacher.
这里有幼稚园老师的缺
Yeah, but what made you become a kindergarten teacher?
为何要教幼稚园？
I mean, it is a bit unusual.
有点儿不寻常
John is a bit unusual.
约翰是与众不同
Well... You are.
你是不同
I was born in Austria.
我生于奥地利
My father was a teacher.
家父当教师
My mother was a teacher. So is Ursula. Ja.
家母当老师 乌苏拉也是
We have a tradition in Austria where we follow the footsteps of our parents.
我们奥地利人 子女继承父母之业
So when I moved to this country...
这所以现在来到美国
I taught geography and physical education in Arizona...
我曾经在亚利桑那州教地理和体育
and then I coached basketball at an all-girls school in Rhode Island, but...
后来当篮球教练 教罗德岛的女孩
none of it made me really happy.
不过以上工作都不愉快
Why weren't you happy? Ja. Why weren't you happy?
为什么不愉快？对 为什么不愉快？
Well, I got tired of teaching teenagers... because by the time they came to me...
厌倦了教青少年
I felt there wasn't much I could do with them.
对青少年我没什么助益
I realized that the real action is in kindergarten.
幼稚园学习阶段才重要
How long have you been teaching kindergarten?
教幼稚园多久了？
It's my second day.
第二天
Oh.
哦
Ooh, excuse me, but it's good.
对不起
It is good.
不过好吃 好吃
Thanks again.
再次感谢 很愉快
Nice to meet you.
非常谢谢 很高兴见到你
Thank you. Bye.
再见
I had a great time. Ja, me, too.
我很开心 是呀 彼此
Well, Kimble, I think you scored.
金霸 你有搞头了
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
哇 哇 哇
What are you talking about? I'm only interested in her
你胡扯些什么
because she works at the school.
基于同事关心 我才对他感兴趣
She knows the children and the parents.
她对亲子都熟悉
If you were any stiffer... we could take you surfing.
你若再死板一点 可当做冲浪板
Now, I know you like that woman. What is your problem?
你喜欢她 顾忌什么？
The only problem I've got is that I'm doing your job.
我代你的差使
You should be cleaning up the paint
应该是你清除漆污
and reading stories about bears that go shopping.
读小熊采买的故事
I'm stuck with your job. Yeah. You are.
卡在你的任务上 你卡住了？
That's right. I am.
我是卡住
Look, you're going to be out of here in a few days.
过几天你就能脱身
You told me yourself you had a few good leads.
刚才你还说有好主意
You'll be back dealing with junkies and murderers in no time.
不久就能再抓毒虫和凶手了
They're pushing me around.
他们逼得我团团转
Who?
谁？
The kids.
小孩子
They're walking all over me.
淘气不听话
Listen, Kimble.
听我说
You got to handle this like any other police situation.
拿出警察的手段来对付
You walk into it showing fear... you're dead...
怀着惧意进教室 你死定了
and those kids know you're scared.
小孩看得出你怕了
No fear.
不怕
Today we're going to play a new fun game.
今天玩新的游戏
It's called " police school."
叫做"警察学校"
I'm going to be your sheriff.
我当警长
You're going to be my deputy trainees.
你们当受训学员
Come on.
来吧
Stop whining.
不要叫苦
You kids are soft. You lack discipline.
你们软弱 缺少纪律
Well, I've got news for you. You are mine now. You belong to me!
你们在我掌握中 属于我
You're not going to have your mommies here to wipe your tushies.
妈妈不在这里 帮你们擦屁股
Oh, no. It's time to turn this mush into muscles.
锻炼肌肉的时候到了
No more complaining. No more, " I have to go to the bathroom."
再也不准嚷着上厕所
There is no bathroom!
没有厕所
Now, the first thing the deputy trainees have to learn
受训第一件事要学习
is to freeze whenever you hear this.
一听到哨音就静止
Now, the next time you hear this whistle...
再听到哨音
each one of you get one toy.
每个人拿一件玩具
How many?
几件？
One!
一件
Good. Then bring it back to the carpet...
很好 拿到地毯上
pronto. Ready?
动作要快 预备？
Wait for it.
等一下
Wait for it. Sit down.
等哨音响 坐下
Ready?
预备？
Go quickly. Get your toy.
起 快 拿玩具
Go. Go for it. Yes. Very fast.
走 去拿玩具 动作快
Good. Quickly. Bring the toy back to the carpet.
好 快 带玩具回到地毯上
Bring it back to the carpet.
拿了回地毯上
Quick, quick, quick. Back to the carpet. Quickly.
快 快 快 回地毯上 快
Emma.
恩玛
Emma...
艾玛…
take your toy to the carpet.
带玩具到地毯上
I'm not a policeman. I'm a princess.
我不是警察 是公主
Take your toy back to the carpet.
带玩具到地毯上
I'm not a policeman! I'm a princess.
我不是警察 是公主
Take it back!
带回地毯上
All right.
好嘛
Very good.
很好
You did very well.
做得好
Now we're going to play another game.
再玩一种游戏
When you hear two whistle blows...
听到哨音两响
take your toy back where you got it and come right back. How many whistle blows?
每人把玩具归原位 回到地毯上 几响？
Two! Two!
两响 两响
Good. Ready?
很好 准备好
Go.
起
Come on. Come right back to the carpet.
回到地毯上
Yes. It works. This is great.
这招管用 好极了
Faster, faster. Come on.
快一点 加油
Yes. Come back. Terrific. This is working. Wait.
妙极了 这招奏效 漂亮
I mean, you're very good deputies.
我是说你们是好警察
Your sheriff is proud of you.
警长觉得光荣
1, 2, 3, 4.
一 二 三 四 一 二 三 四
一 二 三 四
1, 2, 3, 4.
Wait! Take me.
等等 带我去
Down. Up. Down.
下 上 下
Yes, yes, yes!
是的 是的 没错
You've got it.
你已经得到了它
Yes, Wanda. Good.
是的 万达 好
Very good.
挺好
Big circles. Big circles.
大圈 大圆圈
Good.
好
Now do the same thing. Way back.
现在重复做同样的动作
And down in big circles.
和向下的大圆圈
Big circles.
大圈
Yes.
是的
This is a fire drill!
火警演习
This is a fire drill. Run to the door.
火警演习 跑到门口
Dominic, don't forget Ferret.
多明尼 别忘了雪貂
Yes. It's a fire drill. Come on.
对 火警演习
Oh, this is terrible.
慢得可怕
Come on. Come on.
来吧 来吧
29 29
二十九  二十九
三十
三十一
三十二
三十三
One more. Come on. Down and up. Yes!
再做一下 仰卧起坐
Yes! Zach is the winner.
柴克得胜 为他鼓掌
Come on, you guys.
来吧 你们这些家伙
March, 2, 3, 4.
齐步走 二 三 四
前进 二 三 四
Swing your arms. 2, 3, 4.
手臂摆动 二 三 四
Swing them high. 2, 3, 4.
手臂抬高 二 三 四
1, 2, 3, 4.
一 二 三 四
Wow.
哇塞
1, 2, 3, 4!
一 二 三 四
Reading, writing, arithmetic.
读书写字作算数
Reading, writing, arithmetic!
读书写字作算术
Too much homework makes me sick.
功课太多倒胃口
Too much homework makes me sick!
When it's time to pass the test...
考试及格时
kindergarten is the best.
幼稚园里顶呱呱
Kindergarten is the best.
Yay!
耶
E-I-E-I-O
咿呀咿呀哟
And on that farm he had a duck
农场里面有只鸭
E-I-E-I-O
咿呀咿呀哟
All right. Take your milk.
拿牛奶喝
It makes you big and strong.
喝了高又壮
It's story time, Mr. Kimble. All right.
金霸老师 讲故事时间
We all like this one... and if you read us a story now...
我们要听这个
everybody will go to sleep. All right.
现在讲这故事大家会睡觉
"我们小时候"
I used to read this to my son.
我曾念这本给儿子听
What's his name?
他叫什么名字？
Who?
谁？
Your son.
你儿子
Oh, Alex is his name.
他叫亚历
Where is he?
他在那里？
He lives with his mother.
同他妈住
You see, his mother and I...
是这样
we are...
他妈和我
Divorced. I know. What's a divorce?
离婚了 我晓得 离婚是什么？
It's when your daddy lives someplace else
就是你爸住别处
and comes over to take you places...
有时候来带你去玩
and your mommy says he's a deadbeat.
你妈骂他赖帐
No. It's when the daddy doesn't want to see his little boy anymore.
就是爸爸不想再看到儿子
That's not what it is.
不是不想
Why don't you want to see your little boy?
为什么你不想看儿子？
Was he bad?
他不乖？
No, he was not bad.
不是 他不是不乖
It wasn't his fault at all.
完全不是他的错
You see...
是这样 他妈和我
his mommy and I, we just nev...
我们合不来
Just sit down, okay?
坐下好不好？
Let me just start reading. Why don't you all lie down?
我来念 你们都躺下
Okay.
好
Good. And rest.
很好 休息
"If you were a bird and lived on high
假如你小鸟住在高处
you'd lean on the wind when the wind came by.
风吹过来你随风翱翔
You'd say to the wind when it took you away...
你对飘送你的风说
That's where I wanted to go today.
今天我要去的地方
Where am I going? I don't quite know.
上那儿去？我不清楚
What does it matter where people go?
人上那儿去有什么关系？
Down to the wood where the bluebells grow.
到森林里野风信子花开处
Anywhere. Anywhere.
那里都好 随便何方
I don't know.
我不知道
Huh!
咦
Hi.
嗨
你好
I didn't mean to startle you.
不是故意惊吓你
I must have dozed off.
一定是我睡着了
I can't believe you got them all to sleep.
想不到你能哄他们睡着
I worked them hard.
我令他们劳动
I was wondering if...
不知你可愿赏光
you'd like to come to my place for dinner tomorrow night.
明天到我家吃晚饭
I would like that.
我愿意
Yes.
是的
Great. Well, here are the directions.
好 这是方向指南
How about 6:30, 7:00?
六点半至七点
That would be fine.
好呀
What?
怎么了？
Um...
嗯
You... You've got a little mustache.
你长胡子了
Oh, it must be from the milk.
喝牛奶沾到
Well, I'd better get back to class.
我得回教室去
I'll see you tomorrow.
明天见
See you tomorrow.
Freeze!
不准动
No!
不要
No.
This is Henry Shoop...
这是亨利舒普
my fiance.
我未婚夫
Hi.
你好
Your fiance?
你未婚夫？
Yeah, my fiance.
我未婚夫
Henry, this is obviously my partner...
亨利
John Kimble. Oh, jeez.
显然这是我的搭档 约翰金霸
Uh...
呃
Hi. How you doing?
你好吗？
Let me get this... and I'll be right out.
我拿个枕头 马上出来
Oh!
哦
It's okay, honey.
亲爱的 不要紧
I'll be right out.
马上出来
It's my birthday.
我过生日
Well, congratulations.
恭喜 谢谢
Thanks. He came up here just to surprise me.
他老远跑来令我惊喜
And he made me my favorite... pasta a olio.
还做了我爱吃的 意大利油面
I love you, Henry.
亨利 我爱你
I love you, too, Phoebes.
我爱你
Uh... Well, I've got to head back tonight. I've got to work.
今夜要赶回去上班
Henry's a chef. I'm a chef.
亨利当厨师 我当厨师
You're marrying a chef? I'm marrying a great chef.
你要嫁给厨师？手艺高超
That figures.
可想而知
You mean that, a great chef?
我的手艺好？真的？
Of course. You're a genius, Henry.
你是天才 不仅是手艺好？
Not just a good chef?
幸会
Well, nice to meet you. Congratulations. Happy birthday.
恭喜 生日快乐
Thanks. You want some of this?
我喜欢 你不认为煮的太烂？
It wasn't overcooked? You're the best. It wasn't a little overcooked?
有韧性 正合我胃口
No. Al dente.
不 意大利面
Zach.
柴克
Excuse me. I'm John Kimble, Zach's teacher.
我是金霸 柴克的老师
I didn't know he was following me.
他跟着来我不知道
Hi. I've been leaving messages on your machine.
我对答录机留了话
I'm sorry. Things have been hectic.
我没有空回
What about now?
现在呢？
Uh...
呃
Go for a little walk. Your teacher and I have to talk.
柴克 去散步 我和老师讲话
Uh...
呃
I know what this is about.
我知道你要谈的事
I suppose you saw the bruises on Zach's legs?
你看到柴克腿上的瘀伤
My husband has started counseling about this. He's been going for three weeks now.
三周以前我先生 接受精神治疗
Please don't bring the school system into it. It will make matters worse.
报告校方只会使事态严重
He's beating you, too?
他也打你？
If he wasn't going to counseling... I could see the point of saying something...
要不是他就医你会报告？
but I'm sure there won't be any more occurrences.
相信再也不会发生
You won't say anything, will you?
你不会说出去吧？
Please?
拜托
If he does it again, I press charges.
他若再打人我要控告他
Zach.
柴克
You got the stuff?
有没有货？
Thanks, man.
谢了 伙计
Here, lady. I gave her your stuff. Where's the rest of my money?
你的货给她了 尾款在哪儿
Who are you, old lady?
老太太 你是谁？
Your fairy godmother.
你的神仙教母
Come in.
进来
Hi. It took all day... but I found out Zach Sullivan and his mother...
调查一整天 柴克苏利文和克利
aren't related to Crisp. I just found out.
非亲非故 我知道了
Oh. I got a bottle of wine for your big date... It's not a date, I know.
买一瓶酒供你约会用 不是约会 我晓得
But Joyce shouldn't think that.
但是别让乔伊丝起疑
Thanks. I don't think it's a good idea.
这不太好吧
Why not?
为什么？
Quickest way to slip up doing undercover work
违反平时的作风
is doing things you normally wouldn't do.
会暴露密探身份
Wait a minute.
等一下
You mean you wouldn't take wine to a woman who's invited you for dinner?
你是说你赴女人的约会 一向不带美酒相赠？
Of course you would.
当然要带
And flowers as well. Here you go.
还要赠鲜花 拿去
She'll love them.
包她欢喜
Well, here we are.
就是这里
Wow. This is quite a place. They must be paying you
哇塞 好漂亮
a lot more than they're paying me.
你的薪水比我多
I wish it was my house.
但愿房子是我的
It belongs to a friend of mine.
朋友的房子
After the divorce, he said we could stay here
他让我们住 我们负责维护
in exchange for keeping the place up.
你的朋友真好
You must have nice friends.
是的
Yes, I do. Dinner won't be ready for a few minutes.
菜马上就好
Can you start a fire?
能否生个火？
It shouldn't be a problem.
这个好办
I'll show you where the wood is.
我带你去拿柴
All right!
好
Come on. Come on!
跟我来
Right here.
在这儿
In here.
钻进去
This is my secret hiding spot.
这是我躲藏的密窟
Wow. This is amazing.
哇塞 了不起
I made it myself. What's this?
我亲手盖的
Don't touch that! It's a laser...
这是什么？当心 强力死光炮
and it'll burn a hole right through you.
好 我当心
Okay. I'll be careful. Oh, don't shoot.
不要开枪
- Boom! Boom! - Don't shoot.
-嘣 嘣… - 不要开枪
I put up these lasers to protect us.
架死光枪保卫我们
To protect you from what?
防什么？
The bad people.
防坏人
Do you want to see something else?
要不要看别的？
Come on.
走
What?
看什么？
See that?
看到了吗？
You mean the tower?
你是说发波台？
I'm going to plant one of my lasers on that antenna.
我要在天线上架一座死光炮
But I'll have to do it at night.
不过要在夜里进行
Otherwise the bad people will know where it is.
要不然坏人会知道位置
Last one to the table is a rotten banana!
最后上桌的是烂香蕉
Have you guys had fun?
你们男生开心吧？
Yeah. Be right out!
我马上出来
What you doing in there?
你进来干什么？
I'm lost.
我很失落
Where is the dining room? This house is huge.
迷路了 餐室在那儿？房子太大
- Follow me, silly. - Whew.
- 傻子 跟我来 - 呼
These are beautiful pictures of you and Dominic.
你们的照片很漂亮
Thank you.
谢谢你
When I was putting Dominic to bed... he mentioned you had a son, too.
多明尼说你有个儿子
That's right. But I'm divorced.
是的 不过我离婚了
I'm lucky. My ex got remarried to a very nice man.
幸运的是前妻再嫁了好老公
He's really good to my son.
他对我儿很好
I see him a lot.
我可以常看他
What about your ex-husband?
你的前夫
Does he see Dominic a lot?
有没有常来看多明尼
Uh, no.
没有
After the divorce, he moved back to France.
离婚之后他回法国了
What about child support and alimony?
教育孩子和赡养费呢？
Does he take care of you?
他是否供给？
I'm sorry about being so personal.
对不起 我问到隐私
I was so glad to see him go I didn't worry about that part.
他走我就高兴了不求他供养
Dominic doesn't even remember him. I prefer it that way.
多明尼记不得他 这样最好
Are you sure?
真是这样？
Yeah.
是的
Why?
为何问起？
Well, Dominic was talking to me about having to move around a lot
多明尼跟我谈到
to keep the bad people away.
常常迁移躲避坏人
Bad people? Something about having to leave
坏人？
in the middle of the night
他谈到半夜离家
and leave his toys behind.
丢下玩具
Oh, God.
哦 上帝
I thought he'd forgotten about that.
我以为他忘了
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to upset you.
对不起 我无意提伤心事
It's not your fault.
不能怪你
The truth is, my ex-husband is a walking nightmare.
我的前夫是活生生的梦魇
He didn't leave us, we left him.
他没弃我们 是我们弃他
He found out where we were and tried to kidnap Dominic.
他曾找到我们要带多明尼走
He doesn't know where we are now...
现在他不知我们下落
and I'd like to keep it that way.
我要保持这样
Of course.
当然
I'm glad he's in France
幸亏他在法国
and doesn't live nearby.
不是在附近
He doesn't live in France.
他不是在法国
I told Dominic that he lived in France.
在法国是对多明尼说的
I didn't know who my ex-husband was when I married him.
结婚之初我不了解他的为人
I was young and stupid, and I made a mistake.
当时年轻愚昧走错了
I don't want Dominic to pay for it.
我不要连累多明尼
Look, nobody around here knows anything about this.
这段往事这儿的人都不知道
I can't even believe I told you.
我居然对你说出来
You have to promise me you won't tell anyone.
答应我不告诉别人
You can trust me.
你可以信赖我
That's very good. Perfect.
这是非常好的 完美的
Okay. Let's try it again. Mary, you first.
玛莉 我们再试 你先
Fourscores and seven years ago.
八十七年以前
Our forefathers brought...
我们的祖先…
Four fathers?
四个祖宗？
Mr. Kimble, did Lincoln have four fathers?
老师 林肯有四个爸爸？
Uh... I had three fathers...
我有三个爸
One named Walt, two named Ralph.
一个叫华德 二个叫雷夫
Did Lincoln have four mothers?
林肯可有四个母亲？
As a matter of fact, he had two mothers. Unfortunately, the first one died.
他有二个母亲 第一个先死
I knew it.
我就知道
Um... Okay. Let's take a break. Come on.
好 休息一下 听话
I want you to walk around in a circle. Go.
你们给我绕圈走
Start. Come on.
绕 快点
Well, Joyce's story about the house checked out.
乔伊丝的"房事"无误
It belongs to a guy who only uses it during the ski season.
滑雪季节屋主才来住两周
She's got under $1,000 in the bank...
她有一千元存款
no stocks, no bonds,
没租保管箱
no other assets under the name Joyce Paulmarie.
她的本名之下别无恒产
Her teacher's salary is less than mine, which is pathetic.
薪水比我少 真可怜
Keep looking. Check for offshore accounts under Dominic's name...
再查 调查可有国外户头
She doesn't live like someone with millions of dollars.
她的生活不像是有几百万元的人
She doesn't even seem the type.
她不像这类人
Kimble, this might not be her.
金霸 可能不是她
It's got to be her.
一定是她
Why? Because she doesn't want to have
为什么？
anything to do with her ex-husband?
因为她同前夫恩断义绝？
I know it's her.
我知道是她
Know what I think?
可知我的看法？
You want it to be her.
你指望就是她
You really like her, and it's scaring you.
你真心喜欢她 所以吓得要死
Excuse me! Surprise!
对不起 意外吧
Ladies! Ladies, surprise.
各位女士 出乎意表
Obviously, I'm not into baking cakes...
显然我不擅长烘制蛋糕
so I brought these little things to donate for the raffle prizes.
所以我捐这个作摸彩奖品
Who the hell is that?
那女人是谁？
She's the one I was telling you about.
我跟你提的女人
Her husband ran away with another guy.
她老公跟男人私奔
It's been terrible for her.
令她很难受
You're not getting mellow on me, are you?
你不是心软了吧？
3, 4. 1, 2, 3... Hi.
齐步走 一 二 三 四
Come on. 1, 2, 3, 4.
来吧 一 二 三 四
Come on. Go, go.
走呀
I see they stuck you with the Gettysburg Address this year.
今年要你的班朗诵 盖茨堡宣言
They sure did.
不错
Company, halt!
部队 立定
Um...
庵
About last night...
昨夜的事
I've been thinking about it, and...
我仔细想过
I'm glad I told you all those things.
对你说出来我很高兴
So am I.
我也高兴
Um... I-I better get going.
我得走了
Yeah. I have to get going, too.
我也得走了
Is everything okay?
一切顺利吧
Yeah.
是呀
See you tomorrow at the fair.
明天同乐会见
I'm looking forward to it.
我盼望明天
What are you looking at? Ha ha ha!
你看什么？
Shh!
嘘
March! 1, 2, 3, 4.
齐步走 一 二 三 四
I was just talking to the teacher, that's all.
我同那位老师讲话 如此而已
Yeah. Don't laugh.
不要笑
Okay. I'm proud of you. Keep going.
我以你们光荣 前进
I'm sorry Zach's late. The car wouldn't start.
柴克迟到 抱歉 车子抛锚
You be a good boy. I love you.
要听话 我爱你
Hi, champ. Oh!
嘿 冠军
What's the matter?
怎么回事？
Oh, no.
不像话
I fell down again.
我又跌跤了
Hey, wait a minute.
喂 等一下
Uh...
呃
I forgot to close the door to the basement...
地窖门没关 害柴克摔下去
and Zach had a bad fall.
医生说不要紧
You all say the same thing, "He fell down."
老说摔倒 没有新解的词儿？
Don't you have anything better to say?
事实如此
I don't have to justify myself to you!
我不必向你解释
You have no right talking to me like that.
你没资格质问我
How are you doing? You must be the Mr. Kimble we hear so much about.
一定是金霸先生 久仰
You must be the Mr. Kimble we hear so much about.
You hit the kid, I hit you.
你打小孩 我打你
You bastard!
你浑帐
You're not worth it.
你不值我动手
I'm pressing charges against you.
我要告你虐待儿童
Excuse me, everybody.
对不起 借光
I'm sorry. I shouldn't have hit the man... especially in front of the children.
对不起 我不该当着同学打他
It was a mistake.
这是我的错
I checked you out.
我查过你的底细
There is no record of you ever having taught at any public school...
你没有在学校任教的资历
in California or anywhere else.
在加州或别处都没有
Mr. Kimble... you have no teaching experience whatsoever, do you?
金霸先生 你没有教学经验对不对？
Someone finally noticed.
总算有人察觉
I thought the introduction of a ferret was a horrible idea...
带雪貂来不应该
but the children seemed to like it.
不过孩子都喜欢
I thought the use of your police whistle was outrageous...
你用哨子指挥学童太离谱
That's all I could think of.
只有这法子
Please allow me to finish.
拜托 让我说完
Sorry.
对不起
But it worked.
不过方法管用
I have no idea what kind of police officer you are...
你是什么样的警察 我不清楚
but you're a very good teacher.
不过却是优秀的老师
Thank you.
谢谢你
Now, will you tell me something? Don't lie.
请你告诉我 不要撒谎
What did it feel like to hit that son of a bitch?
揍那个浑帐东西的 感觉如何？
It felt great.
很痛快
Yeah.
呀
Well, tomorrow morning. Bright and early.
明天早上 早点来上课
Thank you. Yeah.
谢谢你
Yeah, that's her. And there goes our goddamn case.
对 就是她
Tell O'Hara and Kimble their witness is dead...
我们的案子泡汤了
so Crisp is going to walk.
通知金霸他们 克利要出来了
We want them back here. We've got lots of other cases to clear.
召他们回来 其他案子很多
O'Hara says they think they've located the wife.
他们认为找到逃妻了
And the money?
钱呢？
They're looking into it.
正在调查
Have them tell the wife
放屁
we're letting Crisp go, and he knows where she is.
叫他们通知逃妻克利 知其下落
If she wants police protection, she'll produce the money.
若要警方保护 就得交出脏款
Sorry it took so long, Cullen.
耽误救你 抱歉
Hey, you're looking great.
气色很好
I love you, Mother.
妈 我爱你
We're going to be a family again, son.
我们全家快团圆了
"爱莎莉亚同乐会"
Go!
起跑
Fourscore and seven years ago Fourscore and seven years ago
八十七年以前
our forefathers brought forth on this continent ...
我们的祖先在这新大陆…
a new nation a new nation
建立新国家
conceived in liberty conceived in liberty
生于自由理念
and dedicated to the proposition and dedicated to the proposition
为人人生而平等的主张
that all men are created equal that all men are created equal
献身奋斗
and that government and that government
而致力维护
of the people by the people
民有 民治
and for the people
民享的政府
shall not perish from this earth.
不坠于世
Thank you very much.
谢谢各位
Oh! I'd like to introduce you to our kindergarten teacher.
我来介绍 我们的幼稚园老师
He came to us as a substitute teacher...
他是来代课
and he's proven to be a wonderful asset.
他的表现证明 他的价值非凡
Let's welcome him into our community
欢迎他来我们的社区
and hope that he considers staying on a permanent basis.
但愿他考虑永久居留
Ladies and gentlemen...
各位女士先生
Mr. John Kimble.
约翰金霸先生
Nice town. Hmm.
好城镇
Ahh! Smell that fresh air.
空气新鲜
We should think about buying something up here...
我们应该在这里置产
like some log cabin in the woods near a lake.
买一栋滨湖的森林木屋
Kids love that outdoor kind of stuff.
小孩喜欢户外活动
I'll be in the pharmacy.
我到药房去
Try not to step in anything.
不要惹事生非
I'd like to help you. But we're pretty much out of the race cars... unless...
我帮你挑选 玩具赛车卖完了
This is the last one.
只剩这套样品
It's still in great shape.
它的造型仍旧这么棒
If you don't mind waiting, I'll wrap it up.
情况很好 我给你打九折
I'll knock 10% off... I have a better idea. I'll pay you twice what he's charging.
今天你走运 我加倍跟你买
I promised my boy I'd get him one.
我答应给儿子要这个
I'd love to help you... but my kid's been bugging me since Christmas.
抱歉 我儿子要这个
I'll pay you four times what it's worth. Get your kid something even better.
我出四倍钱跟你买
Sorry. Can you gift-wrap it?
抱歉 能不能包装？当然可以
Hanna, could you wrap that, please? No harm in trying.
我出高价没有恶意
Tourists.
观光客
Great, Dominic. You're doing well.
多明尼 很好
I'll wait over here for you, okay?
我在这边等你
Okay.
好
Great day, huh?
天气真好
We've run out of time.
时间紧迫
We've got to press Joyce now.
要对乔伊丝施压力
What do you mean?
为什么？
Cindy O.D.'d last night.
昨夜仙蒂死了
Shit.
可恶
They released Crisp this morning. He's probably on his way here.
克利获释 可能已前来此地
Salazar said if Joyce is Crisp's wife...
组长要我转告你
she's got to cooperate about the money...
若乔伊丝是克利之妻
or she gets no police protection.
交出脏款 否则警方不会保护她
Bastard.
浑蛋
Ursula, how are you?
乌苏拉 你好吗？
What?
什么事？
I've got to tell you the truth.
我要跟你说实话
Her name's not Ursula.
她不叫乌苏拉
She's not my sister.
不是我妹子
I beg your pardon?
什么？
We're not who you think we are.
不是你以为的身份
What is this?
什么意思？
We're police officers.
我们是警察
We know who you are... Rachel.
瑞雪 我们知道你的身份
This is a joke, right?
开玩笑
No. This is no joke. You took $3 million.
不是 你卷三百万元潜逃
I think...
你弄错
Crisp knows where you are. He could be here any minute.
克利知道你的下落 他要来
Where's Dominic?
多明尼呢？
You'll get immunity for your testimony...
作证可以免罪
but we need you to help us.
但你要帮警方
Where's Dominic?
多明尼呢？
On a pony. We'll offer protection if you tell us about the money.
在骑马 你得说出钱的下落
There's no money, you son of a bitch.
浑帐 没有钱
There never was!
根本没有
No, it's not fair! I'm not finished yet!
不公平 我没骑完
The bad people have found us.
坏人找上我们了
What do you mean, " no money"?
怎么会没钱？
Why are you mad at Mr. Kimble?
为什么对老师生气？
Because he's a jerk.
他愚蠢
Please let me help you!
让我帮助你
Leave me alone!
不要烦我
Joyce, wait! Wait!
等一下
If you didn't take the money...
要是你没卷款
why is he after you?
他要你干什么？
He doesn't want me. He wants Dominic.
不是要我 他要多明尼
She's going to run again.
她又要逃亡了
Yeah.
对
Unless we do something about it.
除非我们助她
Yeah.
对
Hey, snap out of it!
喂 别发呆了
Daryl. Daryl.
达里尔 达里尔
I'm sorry. I wanted to give you a second chance.
我再给你机会
200, cash.
两百元现钞
What is wrong with you?
你怎么搞的？
I'm still not getting through to you, am I, Daryl?
我的话你听不懂？
Mother, got this great surprise for Junior.
我给二世意外之礼
That'll be 57.90.
57元9角
57.90.
Children's aspirin, children's decongestant...
儿童用阿斯匹灵 活血剂
antihistamine.
抗敏感
"直肠体温计"
A thermometer?
体温计？
A lot of flu going around, right?
感冒流行对不对？
It is the season.
正是流行季节
The boy's not sick.
儿子没有病
Doesn't hurt to take precautions.
我是预防
Mother, you are going to make him sick.
妈 你会害他生病
You stuffed all this crap into me, and nothing was wrong.
多年来我都没事 你却逼我吃药
That's why there was nothing wrong with you.
因为吃药才没事儿
Now, how can you argue with that?
怎么说得过你？
Joyce!
乔伊丝
Joyce! Dominic!
乔伊丝 多明尼
You bastard! Where's Dominic?
浑帐 多明尼呢？
I don't know. What happened?
我不知道
You led him here. If he has Dominic, I'll kill you.
你引他来 小孩若丢了我跟你拚了
Stop it!
住手
Let go of me!
放开我
We'll find him. Stop it.
会找到他 别胡闹
We'll find him.
会找到他
Dominic!
多明尼
Did he say anything before he left?
他走之前说过什么？
He said something about getting his lasers.
说什么去拿死光
Lasers?
死光？
I think I know where he is.
我也许知道下落
Aah! Help!
啊哈 帮帮我
Help! Help!
救命
Somebody! Help!
来人呀 救命
Hold on!
多明尼 别动
I'll get him down.
当心
Help!
救命
Hold on. I'm right here.
不要动 我来了
Good boy. All right. Just hold on.
孩子 别动
Okay. Just hold on.
抱紧我
Oh, good. Okay.
很好 好
I was going to put the lasers in the antenna.
我想在天线上架死光炮
I know. Don't worry about anything now.
我知道 不必耽心了
I got you. Just hold on tight now. Hold on tight, okay?
我抱你 抱紧我 抱紧
Good.
很好
If I lost Dominic... I don't think I could go on living.
若失掉多明尼 只怕我活不下去
You're not going to lose him.
你不会失掉他
That's right. I'm not.
是吗？
Cullen said I stole his money so these creeps would follow us for a reward.
孤冷放风声说我卷款 诱使流氓混混找我好领赏
You don't know what he's like. Oh, yes, I do.
你不了解他
I know him well.
我了解他
That's why I don't want him to get you two.
所以不让他接近你和多明尼
Can't trust you or anybody.
你或别人我都信不过
You can trust me. That's what you said before.
你可以信赖我 你说过这话
And you turned out to be a cop.
结果你竟然是警察
I...
我
I didn't mean to hurt you.
我无心伤害你
I wish I was a kindergarten teacher...
真希望我是老师
but I'm not.
可惜不是
I'm a cop. That's all I know how to be.
我是警察 只懂得办案子
I have to get out of here.
我要离开
You have a son.
你有儿子
If you were me, you'd do the same thing.
换了你也会逃走
I have a son I've hardly seen in seven years.
我已有七年没见儿子
I don't mean anything to him.
我在他心中没分量
My ex-wife got remarried. She doesn't want me to be part of his life.
前妻再婚 不要我干扰她的生活
I lost my family.
我的家破了
I should never have let it happen.
我不该任其破裂
Why are you telling me all of this?
为什么跟我说这些？
I don't want to lose you.
我不愿失去你
I don't want to lose Dominic.
不愿失去多明尼
I swear you'll never have to run from him again.
我立誓让你不必再逃避他
Don't worry about anything, okay? We're going to be right across the hall.
放心 我们就在墙那边
Everything's going to be fine. We just want to be extra careful.
一切都好 我们只是小心起见
Thanks. Don't worry.
别耽忧
Whoo!
喔
All right, all right. Settle down.
好 安静
Good morning.
早安
Good morning, Mr. Kimble.
早安 金霸老师
Sit down.
坐下
It's very nice to see you all again.
又见大家很高兴
Meet my very good friend, Phoebe O'Hara.
见过我的好友菲比
Good morning, Phoebe.
早安 菲比
Miss O'Hara is going to talk to you about something very important.
菲比小姐要跟大家讲要紧事
So pay attention to what she has to say, okay?
大家专心听她讲话
Remember, no fear.
记住 不要怕
Thanks.
谢谢
Yeah?
呀？
Boys have a penis. Girls have a vagina.
男生有小鸡鸡 女生有小屁屁
Well, you taught them the basics. That's important.
你教基本性知识 这很重要
Okay, now...
好吧 现在…
today we're going to talk about something else that's really important.
我们来讲真正重要的
Today we're going to talk about strangers.
今天来谈谈陌生人
If a stranger knocks on your door...
在家里若有生人敲门
never answer the door.
不要应门
Because we never talk to strangers.
因为不理陌生人
Let's say that together.
我们一起说一遍
We never talk to strangers. Right.
我们决不理睬陌生人
Can we talk to kids?
可不可以理睬陌生小孩？
Yeah, it's okay. You can talk to kids.
可以 同小孩讲话没关系
What about dogs?
同狗讲话呢？
Huh?
咦？
Can we talk to dogs?
可不可以同狗讲话？
Yeah, you can talk to dogs.
你可以同狗讲话
But what you can't do...
不可以的是
what you must never ever do is...
决不可以 决不 决不
never talk to strangers.
决不理睬陌生人
On the kindergarten level... we try to emphasize the three C's:
在幼教方面 本校强调3C信条
Caring, courtesy and courage.
关怀 礼貌 勇气
Courage. That's my philosophy, too.
勇气也是我的信条
Are you a single parent, Mr. Green?
葛先生 你是单亲？
No, my wife had to stay behind to complete the sale of our home.
不是 太太在后 处理卖房子事宜
I'm checking the schools before we buy a home here.
迁来之前 她要我探视学校情形
Most kindergarten children can't read yet.
幼稚园生多数不识字
My son can.
我儿识字
He reads at 6? That's good.
六岁就识字？很好
And writes. I taught him myself.
还会写字 我教他
He sounds like a special child.
他好像很特别
He is. He's a great athlete.
是的 他运动也很行
Here's what you've waited for. The kindergarten. Have a look.
幼稚园在这里 请看
Oh, Dominic, Dominic... Dominic is king of the mountain!
多明尼 多明尼是群山之王
Way to go, Dominic.
多明尼 加油
Here's your crown. Congratulations, Dominic. The king of Mount Kimble!
恭喜 多明尼 群山之王
Dominic.
多明尼
He looks odd, but he's a wonderful teacher.
他长相粗粗却是好老师
Yes, I'm sure he is.
是 我相信
Did you see Cullen Jr.?
看到孤冷二世没有？
Yeah, yeah.
看到了
She calls him Dominic. She'd always wanted to name him Dominic.
他叫多明尼
What a dumb name.
她喜欢起这名字 好驴
Put that cigar out. It's unhealthy for the kid.
雪茄熄掉 损小孩健康
Then you make your aeroplane go up into the clouds.
然后你开着飞机冲入云霄
Check it out.
去看看
Right.
右
Okay, stay calm. Okay, it's probably a fire drill.
要冷静 火警演习
Oh, man.
哦 伙计
Kimble, the hallway's full of smoke.
金霸 走道里浓烟密布
Okay, this is a fire drill. Come on.
好 火警演习
This is the real thing.
快走 真有火警
Just the way we practiced.
照练习队形
Go out there.
成两路队形出去
Fast. Just the way we practiced it.
快走 照练习的队形
Come on.
来吧
It's only water. Don't be scared.
洒水 不要怕
Stay close to the wall. Let's go.
贴近墙壁 我们走吧
Come on. Come on.
来吧 来吧
Dominic, stay close to me, okay?
多明尼 紧跟着我
Stay close to me.
跟着我 不要走散
Stay behind me.
留在我后面
Don't get separated.
不要走散了
Aah!
啊哈
Are you all right? Come on. Let's go.
你好吗？起来
Dominic, wait!
多明尼 等一下
Dominic!
多明尼
Help! Somebody help me!
救命 来人呀
Help!
救命
Stranger!
有陌生人
陌生人
Stranger! Stranger! Stranger! Stranger!
陌生人 陌生人
Dominic! Where's Dominic?
多明尼？
Dominic!
上楼 我照顾小孩
Aah!
啊哈
Okay, stay together. Stay together.
跟上 跟上
Stay together. Hold onto your partner.
跟上 抓住同伴
Okay, don't lag behind. Hold onto my hand. Stay together.
不要脱队 牵我的手 跟上
Where's Dominic?
多明尼呢？
He's inside. Kimble's looking for him. Joyce!
在里面 金霸去找他了
Joyce!
乔伊斯
Help!
救命
It's okay. It's okay. I'm not going to hurt you. I'm not going to hurt you.
不要怕 我不伤你 我不伤你
It's okay.
不要怕
I'm a fireman. I help people.
我是消防员 专门救人
Well, where's your hat?
你的头盔呢？
My hat?
头盔？
I love this.
反应快我喜欢
I can't fool my own boy. He's just 6 years old.
骗不过自己的儿子 他才六岁
You're right. I'm no jerk fireman.
你问得好 我不是消防员
I'm going to tell you something, Dominic.
我有事告诉你
It's going to be hard for you to understand...
这件事你很难了解 不过
but you got to believe me.
你得相信我
I'm your father, Dominic.
我是你爸爸
Your father.
你的父亲
Don't you recognize me?
你不认得我了？
No.
不认得
Sure you do. It's me.
当然认得
Don't you remember Twinkle, twinkle, little star?
你忘了 "一闪一闪亮晶晶" ？
We have the same kind of hands.
你看 我们的手形状一样
Don't you remember?
你不记得了？
You're not my father. My father lives in France.
你不是我爸 他住在法国
Your mother told you that... but that's not true!
你妈说的？不是真话
I'm your father! I've been searching for you for five years.
我是你爸 找你五年了
Help! Help!
救命
Dominic, I'm your father. You're going to have to do what I say. Do you understand?
我是你爸 你要相信我要听话
Freeze!
不准动
Don't you know there's a fire?
你们不知道有火警？
We thought it was another drill.
我们以为是演习
Well, get out!
出去
Yes, sir.
是的 先生
Whoa, honey. That's a fire in there.
等一下 里面失火
I got a kid in there.
我要进去
NO way!
不行
I'm a cop. If I need a ticket fixed, I'll call you.
我是警察 如要抽掉罚单我找你帮忙
In the meantime, stay out.
别为难
Go on.
出去 走
All right.
好吧
Quiet, you hear me? Quiet.
安静 听到没有？
No!
不
Rachel!
瑞雪
Let go! Just what I need.
真会添麻烦
Please, let him go. Let him go!
孤冷 请你放了他
How the hell do you get out of here?
怎么出去？
Please, please, don't do this!
请你别这样
You're scaring him!
你吓坏他了
Scared? Of course he's scared.
吓他？他当然怕
You told him lies about me.
我的事你瞒着他
My son doesn't know me because of you.
害得他不认我
Listen! Just listen.
听我说 听着
You stole him from me!
你自我身边偷走他
Please, give him back.
把他还给我
Don't touch him!
不要碰他
Aah! Dominic, I had to do it!
多明尼 我必须动手
I didn't want to do it. She made me.
我不愿意 她逼我动手
Everything's going to be okay, Dominic.
一切都会好
Dominic? Come back.
多明尼？
We're getting out of here.
回来 我们逃出去
Dominic?
多明尼
Going to start a whole new family.
我们重组新家庭
Aah!
啊哈
Dominic!
多明尼
Gotcha!
抓到你了
I love you. Do you understand?
我真的爱你知道吗
Tell me you understand that. Say it. Say it!
跟我说你明白 说呀
I understand.
我明白
Daddy.
叫爸
爸爸
Hold it! Right there.
金霸 站住
Drop it! Hurry!
弃械 快点
Don't. Don't. He's not your hostage. He's your son.
弃械 他不是人质 是你儿子
Drop it. On the floor.
枪丢在地上
You'll do this to your own son?
你拿枪威胁亲生儿子？
Drop it! I'm losing it! Hurry!
弃械 我要失控了 快
Relax. I'm putting it down.
别激动 我弃械
Hurry!
快点
Here it is.
枪在这儿
Here it is. Just don't harm the boy, okay?
Good. Good. That's smart.
好 这才识相
All right.
好吧
Why don't you let the boy go now?
现在放小孩走
The boy is mine! He's my boy!
孩子是我的 他是我儿
You get your own goddamn family!
找你自己的家人
Aah!
啊哈
No!
不
Are you okay?
你好吗？
I'm okay. Get Dominic. Okay.
还好 去找多明尼
Dominic!
多明尼
Where's my grandson?
我的孙子呢？
I don't know.
不知道
Where's my grandson?
我的孙子呢？
Go to hell.
你去死吧
That's where you're going, you son of a bitch!
你才要死 浑帐
You're not so tough without your car... are you?
没有汽车你也不堪一击
Mr. Kimble, are you all right?
金霸先生 你好吗？
Oh, I hate this.
我厌恶吃凉粉
Nah, he doesn't want to eat that.
不要 他不吃
He's a tough guy.
他是硬汉
Tough guys don't eat Jell-O.
硬汉不吃凉粉
I'll come back later.
回头我再来
Hi. Hi. How you feeling?
你觉得如何？
Much better. How about you?
好多了 你呢？
I'll live. Check out of here. This stuff will kill you.
死不了 快出院 这玩艺倒胃
Just don't throw up on me.
别吐得我一身
I'm not going to throw up on you...
不会吐得你一身
but I am going to kiss you.
但我要亲你
Phoebe.
菲比
Thanks.
谢谢你救我
Thanks, partner.
谢谢 伙计
Sure.
没什么
How's everybody feeling today? I brought goodies. Did I do that?
大家好 我带了好东西来
Give me the flowers.
鲜花给我
I got some goodies and...
我有好东西
I got it caught. And something I cooked myself.
勾住了 我为你做的菜
Henry
亨利
I almost didn't recognize you with all your clothes on.
你穿了衣服我没认出来
You look good yourself.
你的气色很好
Aah!
啊哈
Did I... I'm sorry. The wedding.
请他参加婚礼
Yeah. Uh...
呀 呃
You're coming to the wedding, right?
我们结婚请赏光
Is it safe?
安不安全？
I wouldn't miss this for the world.
你们的婚礼我决不错过
So...
那么
where do we send the invitation?
请帖寄到那里？
Hmm?
嗯？
They're all yours.
都交给你了
Hi, kids.
小朋友 好
Mr. Kimble!
金霸老师
I'm back.
我回来了
Yay!
耶
Didn't join the union until...
没有加入工会 直到
Class, excuse me.
各位同学 失陪
Uh-oh. They're going to do it.
他们要做羞羞脸的事